# RYAN NEWPORT

UI/UX Designer<br/>Web Designer

Port Perry, ON ryndesign@gmail.com 905-391-8804

#### SKILLS

Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe XD
Visual Studio Code
Responsive HTML/CSS/SasS
Wordpress CMS
Bootstrap
SEO
AODA Compliance
Mobile Design
Graphic Design
Google Analytics
Google Tag Manager

#### **UNDERSTANDING OF**

PHP and JavaScript
Node.js
Git
AWS

## **INTERESTS**

Drawing/Sketching
Sports
Camping & Hiking
Woodworking

Talented UI/UX Designer with 20+ years experience in completing projects ranging from simple storefronts to enterprise-class, web-based interfaces. Successful in engagement for well-known brands, providing a compelling user experience to improve brand loyalty and customer retention. Self motived & result oriented individual with an artistic background & the ability to design for web and print.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Ravenshoe Group - Web Director

April 2004 - Current

- Lead UI/UX designer working closely with the marketing team to design concepts and mockups on 100+ projects.
- Planned, developed, tested, deployed, and maintained HTML, WordPress web applications.
- Participated in daily scrums to discuss solutions & update project status.
- Maintain websites & applications, including content updates, debugging, enhancements, testing & regular upgrades to ensure usability.
- Monitored emerging UX design trends & practices for useful techniques and cutting-edge developments suitable for integration into future projects.

# **BAM Builder Advertising & Marketing -** Graphic/Web Designer May 2002 - Mar 2004

- Built corporate brands by designing cohesive looks between elements such as logos, brochures, signage and trailer wraps.
- Promoted brand identity by creating company logos & delivering attractive, user-friendly & unique website.
- Developed concepts, target audience, requirements, deadlines & budgets.

# Metropolis Media - Graphic/Web Designer

Jan 2000 - Feb 2002

- Designed website layouts, templates & unique branded looks.
- Creative design for print materials, brochures, banners and signs.

### **EDUCATION**

**Graphic Design Degree -** Durham College, Oshawa, ON 1998 - 2000

**High School Diploma -** Henry Street High School, Whitby, ON 1993 - 1998

\*References available upon request.